<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-06-14T13:44:04+00:00</updated><id>https://peppol.agid.gov.it/feed.xml</id><title type="html">PEPPOL</title><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Publication of the new release of the Peppol BIS3 Invoicing Specification aligned with the Revenue Agency v.2.3 Technical Rules</title><link href="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/en/news/new-release-bis3-en/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Publication of the new release of the Peppol BIS3 Invoicing Specification aligned with the Revenue Agency v.2.3 Technical Rules" /><published>2023-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://peppol.agid.gov.it/en/news/new-release-bis3-en</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/en/news/new-release-bis3-en/">&lt;p&gt;On 13/06/2023 the new release of the Peppol BIS3 Invoicing Specification was released which implements version 2.3 of the Technical Rules of the Revenue Agency relating to the management of European invoices published on 15/05/2022, in relation to the Provision 99370 published on 18/04/2019, whose release note is published at this &lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol-docs.agid.gov.it/docs/docs/ITA/invoice/guide/release-notes-it/main.html&quot;&gt;address&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="en" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">On 13/06/2023 the new release of the Peppol BIS3 Invoicing Specification was released which implements version 2.3 of the Technical Rules of the Revenue Agency relating to the management of European invoices published on 15/05/2022, in relation to the Provision 99370 published on 18/04/2019, whose release note is published at this address.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="it"><title type="html">Pubblicazione nuova release della Specifica Fatturazione Peppol BIS3 allineata alle Regole Tecniche AdE v.2.3</title><link href="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/it/news/new-peppol-bis3-it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pubblicazione nuova release della Specifica Fatturazione Peppol BIS3 allineata alle Regole Tecniche AdE v.2.3" /><published>2023-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://peppol.agid.gov.it/it/news/new-peppol-bis3-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/it/news/new-peppol-bis3-it/">&lt;p&gt;In data 13/06/2023 è stata rilasciata la nuova release della Specifica di Fatturazione Peppol BIS3 che implementa la versione 2.3 delle Regole tecniche dell’Agenzia delle Entrate relative alla gestione delle fatture europee pubblicata il 15/05/2022, in relazione al Provvedimento 99370 pubblicato il 18/04/2019, la cui release note è pubblicata a questo &lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol-docs.agid.gov.it/docs/docs/ITA/invoice/guide/release-notes-it/main.html&quot;&gt;indirizzo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="it" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">In data 13/06/2023 è stata rilasciata la nuova release della Specifica di Fatturazione Peppol BIS3 che implementa la versione 2.3 delle Regole tecniche dell’Agenzia delle Entrate relative alla gestione delle fatture europee pubblicata il 15/05/2022, in relazione al Provvedimento 99370 pubblicato il 18/04/2019, la cui release note è pubblicata a questo indirizzo.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Checking the presence on the SMPs of Participant IDs registered with the codes 9906 and 9907</title><link href="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/en/news/checking-smp-pid/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Checking the presence on the SMPs of Participant IDs registered with the codes 9906 and 9907" /><published>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://peppol.agid.gov.it/en/news/checking-smp-pid</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/en/news/checking-smp-pid/">&lt;p&gt;As previously communicated &lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol.agid.gov.it/en/news/NSO-reminder-expiration-validity-codes/&quot;&gt;( news 31 January 2022: Expiration of codes 9907 (Tax Code) and 9906 (VAT number) )&lt;/a&gt; the Peppol Participant IDs 9906 and 9907 have been deprecated and replaced by codes 0211 and 0210 respectively.
It was also requested to proceed with the registration of the active Participant IDs still certified with the 9906 and 9907 schemes with the new 0211 and 0210 schemes and with the subsequent deregistration of the old Participant IDs on the SML/SMP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As known in version 8.4 of the Peppol Code list, the codes 9906 and 9907 have been removed and therefore we ask you to verify that on your SMP all the registered Participant IDs with the old codes 9906 and 9907 have been eliminated and that the active Participant IDs are register exclusively with the new codes 0211 and 0210.
In case of need for updating, we remind you that this is urgent and that it is necessary to inform customers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="en" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">As previously communicated ( news 31 January 2022: Expiration of codes 9907 (Tax Code) and 9906 (VAT number) ) the Peppol Participant IDs 9906 and 9907 have been deprecated and replaced by codes 0211 and 0210 respectively. It was also requested to proceed with the registration of the active Participant IDs still certified with the 9906 and 9907 schemes with the new 0211 and 0210 schemes and with the subsequent deregistration of the old Participant IDs on the SML/SMP. As known in version 8.4 of the Peppol Code list, the codes 9906 and 9907 have been removed and therefore we ask you to verify that on your SMP all the registered Participant IDs with the old codes 9906 and 9907 have been eliminated and that the active Participant IDs are register exclusively with the new codes 0211 and 0210. In case of need for updating, we remind you that this is urgent and that it is necessary to inform customers.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="it"><title type="html">Verifica della presenza sugli SMP di Participant ID registrati con i codici 9906 e 9907</title><link href="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/it/news/verifica-smp-pid/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Verifica della presenza sugli SMP di Participant ID registrati con i codici 9906 e 9907" /><published>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://peppol.agid.gov.it/it/news/verifica-smp-pid</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/it/news/verifica-smp-pid/">&lt;p&gt;Come comunicato in precedenza  &lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol.agid.gov.it/it/news/NSO-reminder-scadenza-codici/&quot;&gt;(news 31 gennaio 2022: Scadenza codici 9907 (Codice Fiscale) e 9906 (Partita IVA) )&lt;/a&gt; i Participant ID Peppol 9906 e 9907 sono stati deprecati e sostituiti rispettivamente dai codici 0211 e 0210. 
E’ stato inoltre richiesto di procedere alla registrazione dei Partecipant ID attivi ancora attestati con gli schemi 9906 e 9907 con i nuovi schemi 0211 e 0210 e alla successiva deregistrazione dei vecchi Participant ID sull’SML/SMP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come noto nella versione 8.4 della Peppol Code list, i codici 9906 e 9907 sono stati rimossi e pertanto si chiede di verificare che sui vostri SMP tutti i Participant ID censiti con i vecchi codici 9906 e 9907 siano stati eliminati e che i Participant ID attivi siano registrati esclusivamente con i nuovi codici 0211 e 0210. 
In caso di necessità di aggiornamento, ricordiamo che questo ha carattere di urgenza e che risulta necessario fornire comunicazione ai clienti.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="it" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Come comunicato in precedenza (news 31 gennaio 2022: Scadenza codici 9907 (Codice Fiscale) e 9906 (Partita IVA) ) i Participant ID Peppol 9906 e 9907 sono stati deprecati e sostituiti rispettivamente dai codici 0211 e 0210. E’ stato inoltre richiesto di procedere alla registrazione dei Partecipant ID attivi ancora attestati con gli schemi 9906 e 9907 con i nuovi schemi 0211 e 0210 e alla successiva deregistrazione dei vecchi Participant ID sull’SML/SMP. Come noto nella versione 8.4 della Peppol Code list, i codici 9906 e 9907 sono stati rimossi e pertanto si chiede di verificare che sui vostri SMP tutti i Participant ID censiti con i vecchi codici 9906 e 9907 siano stati eliminati e che i Participant ID attivi siano registrati esclusivamente con i nuovi codici 0211 e 0210. In caso di necessità di aggiornamento, ricordiamo che questo ha carattere di urgenza e che risulta necessario fornire comunicazione ai clienti.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Single AP of the PA - technical maintenance notice 28/04/2023 at 13:00-15:30</title><link href="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/en/news/single-ap-maintenance-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Single AP of the PA - technical maintenance notice 28/04/2023 at 13:00-15:30" /><published>2023-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://peppol.agid.gov.it/en/news/single-ap-maintenance-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/en/news/single-ap-maintenance-1/">&lt;p&gt;We inform you that AP Unico of the PA will be subject to a technical maintenance intervention from about 13 to 15:30 on Friday 28 April 2023
During this period it will not be possible to send and receive documents and, in general, the entire Single PA system of the PA will not be available.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="en" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">We inform you that AP Unico of the PA will be subject to a technical maintenance intervention from about 13 to 15:30 on Friday 28 April 2023 During this period it will not be possible to send and receive documents and, in general, the entire Single PA system of the PA will not be available.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="it"><title type="html">AP Unico della PA - avviso di manutenzione tecnica 28/04/2023 ore 13:00-15:30</title><link href="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/it/news/manutenzione-ap-unico-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AP Unico della PA - avviso di manutenzione tecnica 28/04/2023 ore 13:00-15:30" /><published>2023-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://peppol.agid.gov.it/it/news/manutenzione-ap-unico-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/it/news/manutenzione-ap-unico-1/">&lt;p&gt;Si comunica che AP Unico della PA sarà oggetto di un intervento tecnico di manutenzione dalle ore 13 alle ore 15:30 circa del giorno venerdì 28 aprile 2023
Durante tale periodo non sarà possibile inviare e ricevere documenti e, in generale, l’intero sistema AP Unico della PA non sarà disponibile.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="it" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Si comunica che AP Unico della PA sarà oggetto di un intervento tecnico di manutenzione dalle ore 13 alle ore 15:30 circa del giorno venerdì 28 aprile 2023 Durante tale periodo non sarà possibile inviare e ricevere documenti e, in generale, l’intero sistema AP Unico della PA non sarà disponibile.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Implementation of Peppol November Release 2022</title><link href="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/en/news/implementation-peppol-november-2022/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Implementation of Peppol November Release 2022" /><published>2023-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://peppol.agid.gov.it/en/news/implementation-peppol-november-2022</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/en/news/implementation-peppol-november-2022/">&lt;p&gt;We inform you that on 06 February 2023 the updates relating to the November Release 2022 of OpenPeppol became effective, which was highlighted through the communication published on 19 December 2022.
The technical specifications currently in force are available at the addresses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol-docs.agid.gov.it/docs/my_index_fatt.jsp&quot;&gt;Billing&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol-docs.agid.gov.it/docs/my_index.jsp&quot;&gt;Other processes&lt;/a&gt; (simple ordering, complete ordering, pre-agreed ordering, transport document).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The innovations introduced with the November Release 2022 are described in the Release Notes relating to the single process, available at the addresses:
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol-docs.agid.gov.it/docs/docs/ITA/others/guides/release-notes-it/3-order-only/main.html&quot;&gt;Simple ordering&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol-docs.agid.gov.it/docs/docs/ITA/others/guides/release-notes-it/28-ordering/main.html&quot;&gt;Complete Order&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol-docs.agid.gov.it/docs/docs/ITA/others/guides/release-notes-it/42-orderagreement/main.html&quot;&gt;Pre-agreed ordering&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol-docs.agid.gov.it/docs/docs/ITA/others/guides/release-notes-it/30-despatchadvice/main.html&quot;&gt;Transport document&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol-docs.agid.gov.it/docs/docs/ITA/invoice/guide/release-notes-it/main.html&quot;&gt;Billing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also inform you that RGS has published the updated version of the NSO Technical Rules for the issue and transmission of Electronic Orders (v.4.11) containing the indications deriving from the Peppol November Release 2022.
The document is available on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rgs.mef.gov.it/VERSIONE-I/e_government/amministrazioni_pubbliche/acquisti_pubblici_in_rete_apir/nodo_di_smistamento_degli_ordini_di_acquisto_delle_amministrazioni_pubbliche_nso/&quot;&gt;Order Sorting Node page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="en" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">We inform you that on 06 February 2023 the updates relating to the November Release 2022 of OpenPeppol became effective, which was highlighted through the communication published on 19 December 2022. The technical specifications currently in force are available at the addresses: Billing; Other processes (simple ordering, complete ordering, pre-agreed ordering, transport document). The innovations introduced with the November Release 2022 are described in the Release Notes relating to the single process, available at the addresses:</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="it"><title type="html">Entrata in vigore della Peppol November Release 2022</title><link href="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/it/news/issue-peppol-november-2022/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Entrata in vigore della Peppol November Release 2022" /><published>2023-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://peppol.agid.gov.it/it/news/issue-peppol-november-2022</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/it/news/issue-peppol-november-2022/">&lt;p&gt;Si comunica che in data 06 febbraio 2023 sono diventati efficaci gli aggiornamenti relativi alla November Release 2022 di OpenPeppol, di cui si è data evidenza attraverso la comunicazione pubblicata in data 19 dicembre 2022. 
Le specifiche tecniche attualmente in vigore sono disponibili agli indirizzi:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol-docs.agid.gov.it/docs/my_index_fatt.jsp&quot;&gt;Fatturazione&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol-docs.agid.gov.it/docs/my_index.jsp&quot;&gt;Altri processi&lt;/a&gt; (Ordinazione semplice, Ordinazione completa, Ordinazione pre-concordata, Documento di trasporto).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Le novità introdotte con la November Release 2022 sono descritte nelle Release Notes relative al singolo processo, disponibili agli indirizzi:
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol-docs.agid.gov.it/docs/docs/ITA/others/guides/release-notes-it/3-order-only/main.html&quot;&gt;Ordinazione Semplice&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol-docs.agid.gov.it/docs/docs/ITA/others/guides/release-notes-it/28-ordering/main.html&quot;&gt;Ordinazione Completa&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol-docs.agid.gov.it/docs/docs/ITA/others/guides/release-notes-it/42-orderagreement/main.html&quot;&gt;Ordinazione Pre-concordata&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol-docs.agid.gov.it/docs/docs/ITA/others/guides/release-notes-it/30-despatchadvice/main.html&quot;&gt;Documento di Trasporto&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://peppol-docs.agid.gov.it/docs/docs/ITA/invoice/guide/release-notes-it/main.html&quot;&gt;Fatturazione&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Si informa inoltre che RGS ha pubblicato la versione aggiornata delle Regole Tecniche NSO per l’emissione e la trasmissione degli Ordini Elettronici (v.4.11) contenenti le indicazioni derivanti dalla Peppol November Release 2022. 
Il documento è disponibile sulla &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rgs.mef.gov.it/VERSIONE-I/e_government/amministrazioni_pubbliche/acquisti_pubblici_in_rete_apir/nodo_di_smistamento_degli_ordini_di_acquisto_delle_amministrazioni_pubbliche_nso/&quot;&gt;pagina relativa al Nodo Smistamento Ordini&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="it" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Si comunica che in data 06 febbraio 2023 sono diventati efficaci gli aggiornamenti relativi alla November Release 2022 di OpenPeppol, di cui si è data evidenza attraverso la comunicazione pubblicata in data 19 dicembre 2022. Le specifiche tecniche attualmente in vigore sono disponibili agli indirizzi: Fatturazione; Altri processi (Ordinazione semplice, Ordinazione completa, Ordinazione pre-concordata, Documento di trasporto). Le novità introdotte con la November Release 2022 sono descritte nelle Release Notes relative al singolo processo, disponibili agli indirizzi:</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Reporting activity towards OpenPeppol</title><link href="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/en/news/openpeppol-reporting-activity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reporting activity towards OpenPeppol" /><published>2023-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://peppol.agid.gov.it/en/news/openpeppol-reporting-activity</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/en/news/openpeppol-reporting-activity/">&lt;p&gt;It is recalled that, on the basis of paragraph 9.4.8 of the Agreement signed between the Peppol Service Providers and the national Peppol Authority, the Service Providers are obliged to make available to the Peppol Coordinating Authority of OpenPeppol, on a monthly basis, a set of data statistics that allow you to monitor the operations performed on the Peppol network, identify and manage risks and problems within the network itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the information available to date, the reporting activities of the SPs towards OpenPeppol will presumably be launched during the third quarter of 2023 and will concern the periodic collection of data relating to the volumes of incoming and outgoing transactions of the Access Point of the SP.
The relative specifications in the original language are currently available in the test environment at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://test-docs.peppol.eu/reporting/EUR-1.0.0-RC2/tsr/&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AgID will provide further information on this as soon as they are available.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="en" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">It is recalled that, on the basis of paragraph 9.4.8 of the Agreement signed between the Peppol Service Providers and the national Peppol Authority, the Service Providers are obliged to make available to the Peppol Coordinating Authority of OpenPeppol, on a monthly basis, a set of data statistics that allow you to monitor the operations performed on the Peppol network, identify and manage risks and problems within the network itself. Based on the information available to date, the reporting activities of the SPs towards OpenPeppol will presumably be launched during the third quarter of 2023 and will concern the periodic collection of data relating to the volumes of incoming and outgoing transactions of the Access Point of the SP. The relative specifications in the original language are currently available in the test environment at the link. AgID will provide further information on this as soon as they are available.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="it"><title type="html">Attività di Reporting verso OpenPeppol</title><link href="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/it/news/attivita-reporting-openpeppol/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Attività di Reporting verso OpenPeppol" /><published>2023-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://peppol.agid.gov.it/it/news/attivita-reporting-openpeppol</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://peppol.agid.gov.it/it/news/attivita-reporting-openpeppol/">&lt;p&gt;Si ricorda che, sulla base del paragrafo 9.4.8 dell’Agreement sottoscritto tra i Service Provider Peppol e la Peppol Authority nazionale, i Service Provider sono obbligati a mettere a disposizione della Peppol Coordinating Authority di OpenPeppol, con cadenza mensile, un insieme di dati statistici che consentono di monitorare le operazioni eseguire sulla rete Peppol, identificare e gestire i rischi e i problemi all’interno della rete stessa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sulla base delle informazioni ad oggi disponibili, le attività di reporting dei SP verso OpenPeppol saranno avviate presumibilmente nel corso del terzo trimestre 2023 e riguarderanno la raccolta periodica dei dati relativi ai volumi di operazioni in entrata e in uscita dell’Access Point del SP.
Le relative specifiche in lingua originale sono attualmente disponibili in ambiente di test al &lt;a href=&quot;https://test-docs.peppol.eu/reporting/EUR-1.0.0-RC2/tsr/&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AgID fornirà ulteriori indicazioni in merito non appena queste saranno disponibili.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="it" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Si ricorda che, sulla base del paragrafo 9.4.8 dell’Agreement sottoscritto tra i Service Provider Peppol e la Peppol Authority nazionale, i Service Provider sono obbligati a mettere a disposizione della Peppol Coordinating Authority di OpenPeppol, con cadenza mensile, un insieme di dati statistici che consentono di monitorare le operazioni eseguire sulla rete Peppol, identificare e gestire i rischi e i problemi all’interno della rete stessa. Sulla base delle informazioni ad oggi disponibili, le attività di reporting dei SP verso OpenPeppol saranno avviate presumibilmente nel corso del terzo trimestre 2023 e riguarderanno la raccolta periodica dei dati relativi ai volumi di operazioni in entrata e in uscita dell’Access Point del SP. Le relative specifiche in lingua originale sono attualmente disponibili in ambiente di test al link. AgID fornirà ulteriori indicazioni in merito non appena queste saranno disponibili.</summary></entry></feed>